Billy, how are we doing?
>> Doing well. How are you guys doing?
>> Excellent. Doing well. Uh, we got some
of our local media here. So, if you are
all good to go, we are going to go ahead
and get started.
>> Feel free to roll.
>> Whoever's got a question, go ahead.
>> Billy, that USC game, um, what I've
heard, you suffered that knee injury
pretty early in the game and just kept
working. Can you talk a little bit about
what what went into your decision that,
you know, I'm going to continue to play
through this?
>> Yeah. Um, you know, I think whenever you
get the chance and the the medical team,
you know, gives you the the option to go
back out there, it's, you know, it's not
really an option. You you love to go
play with those guys. Um, yeah. So, no
regrets. You know, I love I love playing
the game and I don't take any moment out
there for granted. And, you know, having
the opportunity to get back out there
with my guys was was all I wanted.
Billy, Notre Dame is one of the most
prestigious programs in all of college
football. With that being said, how much
did it mean for you to be a team
captain?
>> Yeah, it was awesome. Uh I love those
guys in that locker room, you know, like
brothers and, you know, to be uh
to be uh you know, thought of as as a
leader in in that uh not only my room
but in the whole locker room is uh it's
a huge honor.
really had you talked to the Bucks much
in the in the draft process. Is this
something you thought might be happening
or
>> Yeah, you know, talked with them, met
with them probably two two or three
times, but uh yeah, had a had a decent
feeling, but uh you know, I think you
never really know until until your
phone, uh starts ringing, but uh yeah,
super fired up for the opportunity. And
what was that moment like when when you
looked down and you saw the 813 and you
with your family like what what was that
moment like? Talk about it. a lot of
gratitude, you know, kind of
kind of uh you know, it's been it's been
a different little journey here the last
couple months, but trying to stay in the
moment with all of it and uh you know,
put my put my foot forward, you know,
and uh you know, super fired up to be in
in Tampa and and in Florida. You know, I
think it's a good fit.
It's one thing to block the guy straight
across from you, but part of your
scouting report is that you have a a
high level of awareness to be able to
pick up blocks from angles that you know
maybe not um predictable. Can you talk a
little bit about how you're able to find
those loopers, those stuners, the
blitzers, and make sure that the pocket
stays clean?
>> Yeah, I think it's number one playing
playing with the guys next to you. Um
it's five is one. um everything's got to
be done together at the offensive line
positions. So, I think that's number
one. And then, you know, you got to be
prepared. Um you got to kind of see
things un unraveling as they're uh um
you know, as they're lined up. You can't
be can't be late with everything or with
anything. Um so, I think those two
things, but uh you know, taking care of
the guys next to you is huge. Billy, how
would you kind of describe your play
style, your mentality when you go out on
the football field?
>> Yeah. Um, you know, love get getting
after guys. Um,
I think I always, you know, try to uh
try to be a good teammate, try to take
care of the guys next to me, but in in
doing so, I like to uh, you know, I like
to play physical. I like uh I like uh
getting after dudes, you know, playing
uh playing the game the way it's
supposed to be played, fast, strong,
powerful.
>> Billy, you blocked for two first round
running backs and Jeremiah and Jadarion.
When it comes to run blocking
specifically, what do you enjoy most
about it? And is it laying guys in the
dirt or
>> I think it's, you know, moving a a man
against his will is is awesome. you
know, there's not many sports where you
can express yourself physically like
that and get after people. And I think,
you know, I never feel more like myself
than when I'm out playing football. And,
you know, run blocking is a huge part of
that for me.
>> I think they they like you as a guard,
obviously, what you played. If you were
to cross trainin, would you be more
likely to step outside to tackle or or
inside to center, do you think?
>> I'd be comfortable wherever. You know, I
uh I love playing ball and uh you know,
finding a way to uh get out there and
help the Buccaneers win football games
is that's number one for me.
>> What do you think? What do you think you
can bring to the Buccaneers?
>> I'm bringing edge, you know. Um I uh I
play the game a certain way and uh you
know, I think that's that's that's
number one. But, uh, you know, I've I
love to win and you know, I'll always
play the game to win. I think that's
that's number one. So, you know, just
getting out there doing everything I can
to uh,
like I said, help this team win ball
games.
>> Billy, this time last year, they they
brought in Benjamin Morrison from Notre
Dame. Do do you know him well?
>> Yeah, I do know Beimo. Yeah, we came in
the same class at uh at Notre Dame and
he uh you know, great dude and great
football player.
>> Bill, you're you're from a small town in
Wisconsin of a population of less than
2,000. Just how much has the journey
from, you know, growing up there to
going to Notre Dame and now being in the
NFL?
>> Yeah. Um
it's awesome. you know, not many people
have have done what I'm I'm doing. And I
think uh you know, it's it's really a
credit to my my family and my community
and you know, I'm just
you know, I'm kind of where the the
light light is shining. But there's a
lot of people that uh that have helped
me get to where where I've gotten and uh
I'm super grateful for them. you know,
my uh my family's awesome. And you know,
growing up in that small community, I
also had a lot of friends and and uh you
know, even
cousins, uncles, you know, who uh you
know, show me the right way to do things
and go about things. And I think that's
that's probably what I remember the most
with throughout my journey. Billy, when
when you look at today, it's obviously,
you know, it's it's an amazing day for
you, but that injury kind of maybe
robbed you of maybe a higher draft slot.
Does that give you any any chip on your
shoulder to motivate that, hey, like
this is where I landed, but this is not
where I end?
>> Yeah, you know, I'm right where I'm
supposed to be. I uh think everything
happens for a reason. I I think this is
a great fit, and you know, I'm always
highly motivated. Um, that's just that's
who I am. Uh, and I I think
motivation isn't isn't something I uh,
you know, I I uh I I look for all the
time, you know, it's always kind of I'm
grateful to kind of have that that
within me. Um, so Bill, your knee, you
full go back to health on that.
>> Full fully healthy. Yep. Ready for camp.
And Bill, your your last name you
pronounce Shrath. Is that right?
>> Correct. Outstanding.
>> If you had a message for any of the
Bucks fans who are watching this right
now, what kind of player what kind of
person are they getting with you?
>> Yeah. Physical
physical guy who uh you know wants to
help the team win. And uh I'll uh you
know, I'll be a I'll be a culture guy. I
spent a lot of time in uh you know the
locker room and in the old line room and
in the facility and I think uh you know
it shows up. I try to bring try to bring
energy to guys and my teammates and and
not take it.
>> All right, Billy. Thank you very much.
Congratulations. Thank you guys.